

CONTACT

hello@markboss.me @

markboss.me

linkedin.com/in/markbboss in

ABOUT ME

I am a researcher at Unity Technologies. Before that, I completed my Ph.D. at the University of Tübingen in the computer graphics group of Prof. Hendrik Lensch. My research interests lie at the intersection of machine learning and computer graphics, with the main focus on inferring physical properties (shape, material, illumination) from images.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.)

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2023

University of Tübingen, Germany Advisor: Prof. Hendrik Lensch

Master of Science (M.Sc.)

Feb. 2016 - Apr. 2018

University of Tübingen, Germany

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)

Sep. 2012 - Feb. 2016

Osnabrück University of Applied Sciences, Germany

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Research Scientist - Unity Technologies - Germany

Sep. 2022 - present

Student Researcher - Google - Germany

Jun. 2021 - Apr. 2022

Research Intern - NVIDIA - Westford, MA

Apr. 2019 - Jul. 2019

Android Developer - zahlz - Osnabrück, Germany

Jul. 2015 - Jun. 2017

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

SAMURAI: Shape And Material from Unconstrained Real-world Arbitrary Image collections

Dec. 2022 - NeurIPS - Mark Boss, Andreas Engelhardt, Abhishek Kar, Yuanzhen Li, Deqing Sun, Jonathan T. Barron, Hendrik P. A. Lensch, Varun Jampani

Neural-PIL: Neural Pre-Integrated Lighting for Reflectance Decomposition

Dec. 2021 - NeurIPS - Mark Boss, Varun Jampani, Raphael Braun, Ce Liu, Jonathan T. Barron, Hendrik P. A. Lensch

NeRD: Neural Reflectance Decomposition from Image Collections

Oct. 2021 - ICCV - Mark Boss, Raphael Braun, Varun Jampani, Jonathan T. Barron, Ce Liu, Hendrik P. A. Lensch

Two-shot Spatially-varying BRDF and Shape Estimation

Jun. 2020 - CVPR - Mark Boss, Varun Jampani, Kihwan Kim, Hendrik P. A. Lensch, Jan Kautz